Analysis of algorithms to go from point A to point B.
From city to city, there are many ways for accomplishing this, either by flight, by bus, by train,
by bicycle or others.
So depending on the availability and convenience we choose, the one that suits us.
Similarly, in computer science, multiple algorithms are available for solving the same problem.
For example, a sorting problem has many algorithms like insertions or selections or quick sort, and
many more algorithms.
Analysis helps us to determine which algorithm must be our most efficient in terms of time and space.
Comment.
You know, the analysis of algorithms.
Comparing algorithms in terms of execution time, memory usage and developer effort, the number of
statements so.
To compare algorithms, let us define if you objective measures like execution time.
Not a good measure as execution times are specific specific to a particular computer.
And number of statement executed like the developer effort.
Not a good measure, since the number of statement varies with the programming languages as well as
the style of the individual program.
And so what is the case of the ideal solution?
Let us assume that we express the running time of a given algorithm as a function of the input size,
and so the function would be f off and and compare these different functions corresponding to running
times.
This kind of comparison is independent of machine time, programming style and et cetera.
I know this may be confused.
It may be confusing for a little bit, but it will be clarified later on in the next videos.
So don't worry, we are keeping step by step and moving step by step.
The master data structures and.